grockit.com 2013-05-19

# Privacy Policy | Grockit

Effective: December 22, 2011

These terms, conditions and policies (“Privacy Policy”) set forth what information about you Grockit, Inc. (“us,” “we,” or “our”) collects, as well as how that information is used, maintained, and, in some cases, shared. It is designed to help you make informed decisions when using Grockit, located at [www.grockit.com](http://www.grockit.com/), the Grockit Facebook application, and any directly associated domains (hereinafter, collectively and equivalently, “Grockit,” the “Grockit service,” or the “Website”).

By using or accessing Grockit, you accept the policies and practices described in this Privacy Policy, and you hereby consent that we will collect, use, and share your information in the following ways.

This Privacy Policy is for the Grockit only and does not apply to, or supercede, the Facebook privacy policy.

### The Information We Collect

When you use Grockit, you provide us with two types of information: personal information that you knowingly choose to disclose to us and information collected by us as you interact with our Website.

When you register with Grockit or accept permissions within Facebook for the Grockit application, you provide us with, or agree to allow Facebook to provide us with, certain personal information such as your name, your email address, and any other personal or preference information that you provide to us. You will also be asked to create a password.

Grockit employs browser cookies and other technologies to collect information about users, such as their IP address, the type of browsers used, web pages viewed, and other information. We take measures to ensure that our cookies do not collect personally identifiable or sensitive information. The aggregate information we collect is analyzed and may be combined with similar aggregate information of other visitors to our Website. You may set your browser to reject cookies; however, this may affect some functions of Grockit.

When you use Grockit, you may transmit information about yourself to us, our partners, or others, through activities which include: setting up your personal profile, forming groups and relationships with other users, playing multi-player games, sending messages to others, performing searches and queries, and otherwise transmitting information through various channels. We collect this information so that we can provide you the Grockit service and offer personalized features. In most cases, we retain this information so that, for instance, you can return to games that you have played or easily access one of your groups on Grockit. When you update information, we usually keep a backup copy of the prior version for a reasonable period of time to enable reversion to the prior version of that information.

You post User Content (as that term is defined in the Grockit Terms of Use, available at <http://grockit.com/blog/main/terms-of-service/> on the Website at your own risk. Although we allow you to set privacy options that limit access to your pages, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot control the actions of other users with whom you may choose to share your pages and information. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that User Content you post on the Website will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Website. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of User Content may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other users have copied or stored your User Content.

Any improper collection or misuse of information provided on Grockit is a violation of the Grockit Terms of Use and should be reported to [privacy@grockit.com](mailto:privacy@grockit.com).

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our Website, we will ask you for information needed to send an invitation to your friend, such as your friend’s email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email or instant message inviting him or her to visit the Website. Grockit stores this information to send this one-time invitation, to register a friend connection if your invitation is accepted, and to track the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at [info@grockit.com](mailto:info@grockit.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

Grockit may also collect information about you from other sources and other users of the Grockit service through the operation of the Website (e.g., photo tags) in order to provide you with more useful information and a more personalized experience.

If you use Grockit outside of the United States, information that we collect about you will be transferred to servers inside the United States and maintained indefinitely, which may involve the transfer of information out of countries located in the European Economic Area. By using Grockit and thereby allowing Grockit to collect information about you, you consent to such transfer and processing of your data.

### Children Under Age 13

Grockit does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register. If you are under the age of 13, please do not attempt to register for Grockit or send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under the age of 13 may provide any personal information to us or on or through the Website. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under the age of 13, please contact us at [info@grockit.com](mailto:info@grockit.com).

### Children Between the Ages of 13 and 18

We recommend that minors over the age of 13 ask their parents for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet, including use of Grockit.

### Use of Information Obtained by Grockit

When you register with Grockit, or connect to Grockit with your Facebook account, you create your own profile and privacy settings. These privacy settings are distinct from privacy settings within your Facebook account. Your profile information, as well as your first name, email and photo, are displayed to people in the groups specified in your privacy settings to enable you to connect with people using Grockit. We may occasionally use your name and email address to send you notifications regarding new services offered by Grockit that we think you may find valuable.

Profile information is used by Grockit primarily to be presented back to you, and edited by you, when accessing the Website. In addition, profile information is presented to others who are permitted to view that information based on your privacy settings. In some cases, where your privacy settings permit it, other Grockit users may be able to supplement information displayed on your profile.

Profile information that you submit to us will be available to users of Grockit who belong to at least one of the groups which you allow to access the information through your privacy settings. Your first name, group names, and any profile picture thumbnail will be available in search results across the Grockit network and those limited pieces of information may be made available to third-party search engines. This is primarily so other users in your groups can find you. People who see your first name in searches, however, will not be able to access your profile information unless they have a relationship to you that allows such access based on your privacy settings.

We may send you service-related announcements from time to time through the general operation of Grockit.

We may use information in your profile without identifying you as an individual to third parties. We do this for purposes such as aggregating how many people are studying for a particular standardized test, and personalizing advertisements and promotions.

We may use information about you that we collect from other sources, such as Facebook, to supplement your profile.

### Sharing Your Information with Third Parties

Grockit allows you to choose the information that you provide to other users through Grockit. Our network architecture and your privacy settings allow you to make informed choices about who has access to your information. We will not provide your personal information to third-party marketers without your permission (your privacy settings to suffice).

We share your information with third parties only in limited circumstances where we believe such sharing is (1) reasonably necessary to offer the Grockit service, (2) legally required or, (3) permitted by you. For example:

We may provide information to third parties to help us bring you the Grockit service. Specifically, we may use third parties to facilitate our business, such as to host the service at a co-location facility for servers, to send out email updates about Grockit, to remove repetitive information from our user lists, or to provide search results or links (including sponsored links). In connection with these offerings and business operations, our service providers may have access to your personal information for a limited time in connection with these business activities. Where we utilize third parties for the processing of any personal information, we implement reasonable contractual and technical protections limiting the use of that information to the Grockit-specified purposes.

We may be required to disclose user information pursuant to lawful requests, such as subpoenas or court orders, or in compliance with applicable laws. We do not reveal information until we have a good faith belief that an information request by law enforcement or private litigants meets applicable legal standards. Additionally, we may share account or other information when we believe it is necessary to comply with laws, to protect our interests or property (including without limitation safety of our employees, users, or others), to prevent fraud or other illegal activity perpetrated through the Grockit service or using the Grockit name. This may include sharing information with other companies, lawyers, agents or government agencies.

We may let you choose to share information with marketers or electronic commerce providers through sponsored groups or other offers on the Website.  
Like many other websites that interact with third-party sites, we may receive some information even if you are logged out from Grockit, or that pertains to non-Grockit users, from those sites in conjunction with the technical operation of the system. In cases where we receive information on users that are not logged in, or on non-Grockit users, we do not attempt to associate it with individual Grockit accounts and will discard it.

If the ownership of all or substantially all of the Grockit business or assets, or individual business units owned by Grockit, Inc. changes, or if we go out of business or enter bankruptcy, your information may be transferred to a new owner. Grockit does not guarantee that any entity receiving such information in connection with such transactions will comply with all terms of this Privacy Policy.

When you use Grockit, certain information you post or share with third parties, including but not limited to your personal information or your games or other learning devices, may be shared with other users in accordance with the privacy settings you select. All such sharing of information is done at your own risk. Please keep in mind that if you disclose personal information in your profile or when posting comments, messages, photos, videos, or other items, this information may become publicly available.

### Links

Grockit may contain links to other websites. Grockit is not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Website to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Grockit.

### Third-Party Advertising

Advertisements that appear on Grockit are sometimes delivered (or “served”) directly to users by third-party advertisers. Such third-party advertisers automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also download cookies to your computer, or use other technologies such as JavaScript and “web beacons.” Doing this allows the third-party advertiser to recognize your computer each time they send you an advertisement in order to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. In this way, they may compile information about where individuals using your computer or browser saw their advertisements and determine which advertisements are clicked. We do not have access to or control of the technologies that may be placed on Grockit by third-party advertisers. Third-party advertisers have no access to your contact information stored on Grockit unless you choose to share it with them via your privacy settings or otherwise.

This Privacy Policy covers our use of cookies and similar technologies on Grockit and does not cover the use of cookies or other tracking technologies by any third-party advertisers. Third party vendors, including Google, show Grockit ads on sites on the internet. Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a Grockit user’s prior visits to Grockit. Users may opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

### Changing or Removing Information

Access and control over most personal information on Grockit is readily available through the profile editing tools. You may modify or delete any of your profile information at any time by logging into your Grockit account. Modified or deleted information will be updated immediately. Removed information may persist in backup copies for a reasonable period of time but will not be generally available to members of Grockit. To deactivate your account, please contact us at [privacy@grockit.com](mailto:privacy@grockit.com).

When you use any of the communication features on our Website to share information with other Grockit users (e.g., posting a group chat message), you generally cannot remove such communications.

### Security

You need to prevent unauthorized access to your account and personal information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account. Grockit takes appropriate precautions to protect our users’ information. Your account information is located on a secured server behind a firewall. However, we cannot guarantee complete security. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time. Because email and instant messaging are not recognized as secure communications, we request that you not send private information to us by email or instant messaging services. If you have any questions about the security of Grockit, please contact us at [privacy@grockit.com](mailto:privacy@grockit.com).

### Terms of Use, Notices and Revisions

Your use of Grockit, and any disputes arising from it, is subject to this Privacy Policy as well as our Terms of Use and all of its dispute resolution provisions including arbitration, limitation on damages and choice of law. We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use at any time. If we make changes, we will post them and will indicate at the top of the respective page the respective policy’s new effective date. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you here, by email, or through notice on our home page. You are bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when you use the Website after such changes have been first posted. We encourage you to refer to this Privacy Policy on an ongoing basis so that you understand our current practices.

### Contacting the Website

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@grockit.com](mailto:privacy@grockit.com). You may also contact us by mail at 500 Third Street, Suite 260, San Francisco, CA 94107.
